



İstanbul, Turkey

□ (+90) 537 730 4283 | Fehmiisener@gmail.com | Gehmiisener | Fehmiisener | Fehmiisener |

"The future is already here – it's just not evenly distributed."

Summary.

Current Software Development Intern at Garanti BBVA Teknoloji. Passionately love problem solving and competition. Always strive to learn and develop new things in Computer Science. Research every innovation and problems that come across, regardless of field or reason. Thanks to this curiosity, can discover new algorithms and new ores.

Interested in the philosophy of computer science, better problem-solving, and clean code. Also develops himself in Backend Development, Data Science, Information Security, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning.

He also researches and listens to music albums from different genres. Plays traditional Turkish musical instrument baglama. Enjoys reading crime and science fiction. Engaged in football, chess and fitness sports.

Work Experience _____

Garanti BBVA Teknoloji

İstanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERNSHIP

Jul. 2021 - Present

- · Implemented several RESTful API and Business Logic in Java, Spring Boot. Deployed using applications such as Git, Jenkins and Sonarlint in accordance with CI/CD processes.
- JUnit tests were written for the developed RESTful APIs.
- Works in accordance Agile Software Development methodologies.

Arçelik Global İstanbul, Turkey

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATION INTERNSHIP

Feb. 2021 - Jul. 2021

- Developed an integrated program with Lucy Security to increase the participation rate in security tests. Used Python, Windows PowerShell, Microsoft SQL Server, System Center Orchestrator and RESTful API.
- Location-based dynamic reports were created to check the status of devices in use across the entire company. Python, Windows PowerShell, Microsoft SQL Server, SQL Server Reporting Services were used.
- User accounts managed. For OneDrive and Outlook, the accounts have been edited and reports created. Developed solutions using Powershell Exchange Online modules.

Publications

Learning to Rank for Text Summarization: Revisiting the Features and Methods for **Turkish Bank Documents**

IEEE INISTA 2021

ACCEPTED CONFERENCE PAPER IN IEEE · F. GOZ, F. SENER, A. MUTLU, K. KUCUK, M. TEMUR · KOCAELI, TURKEY

Aug. 25 - 27, 2021

 This study revisits features and learning to rank algorithms for domain specific Turkish text summarization. Elaborated on the effect of sentencelevel and wordlevel features for text summarization using three learning to rank algorithms that belong to different categories.

Projects ____

TEAM | FADER

ABVAG · Streaming Big Data Analytics

Kocaeli University · Research

Proiect

• Our overall aim is to provide anomaly analysis on large data flowing spatio-temporal.

Mar 2021 - Present

- · Various articles related to the detection of outlier trajectories and drivers have been examined. As a result of the reviewed articles, the pseudocode and implementation of the algorithm have been written.
- · Group Coordination and Planning, Support and Reinforcement of Team Members when the necessary situation. General maintenance, system updates, account managements and security on the Ubuntu Server.
- · Apache Kafka was installed, configured and topics were created to provide continuous data flow to the algorithms
- Apache Cassandra NoSQL database was installed, configured and necessary tables were created to keep data continuously and to analyze using historical data.
- Researches have been made about technologies such as Apache Kafka, Apache Cassandra, Docker.
- Docker Container installations were made to manage all applications and algorithms in a stable and orderly manner. Templates of Dockerfile and docker-compose files were created and shared to set an example for team members.

Team Leader Mar. 2021 - Sep. 2021

• Created a virtual twin for the tomato plant. More efficient growing conditions were modeled according to the current state of the plant. Designed an unmanned ground vehicle for plant controls.

- Developed Machine Learning models to study the state of tomatoes. (for tomato, color, leaf damage and insect detection)
- Developed a mobile application in React Native to follow the current status of vehicle movements and plants.
- All our applications are developed and managed on cloud based Ubuntu Server. User accounts setup, application installations and server
 configured.
- Developed RESTful API with .Net Core and C# for communication between application services.
- Stored the data of the plants in the PostgreSQL database.
- Developed in accordance with DevOps and CI/CD processes.
- Built fully automated CI/CD pipelines on Ubuntu Server for containerized applications using Docker, Jenkins and Github.
- Used Git Version Control system such as Github and developed with teamwork. Releases were managed using Semantic versioning. Detailed documentation was prepared for the releases.

SanAmuze · Creating an Autonomous Virtual Museum

Teknofest Competitions

Mar. 2021 - Sep. 2021

SOFTWARE TEAM

- Designed an unmanned ground vehicle that automatically creates a virtual museum to make children love museums and to include them in education.
- · For a better understanding of the artifacts, 3D models were created automatically using image processing algorithms.
- All our applications are developed and managed on cloud based Ubuntu Server. User accounts setup, application installations and server
 configured.
- Developed a mobile application where children can compare the similarity of their drawings to the artifacts to have fun and get to know the artifacts more closely.
- Developed in accordance with DevOps and CI/CD processes.
- Developed RESTful API with Python Flask for communication between application services.
- Built fully automated CI/CD pipelines on Ubuntu Server for containerized applications using Docker, Jenkins and Github.
- Used Git Version Control system such as Github and developed with teamwork. Releases were managed using Semantic versioning. Detailed documentation was prepared for the releases.

Document Fingerprints Based Text Search Engine in Hierarchical Documents

Tübitak Teydeb

VOLUNTEER TEAM MEMBER

Jan. 2021 - Jul. 2021

- Detection of fingerprints of texts in businesses with large documents, processing/storing these fingerprint data together with the content of the text for later needs and presenting it quickly with a search engine if needed.
- Used Abstractive and Extractive Text summarization techniques. The results were compared with each other.
- · Measurement of document similarities, performance tests and software development activities were carried out.
- Experienced teamwork and collaborative software development environment.

Education

Kocaeli University · Faculty of Engineering

Kocaeli, Turkey

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (BSc) IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING · 4TH GRADE

Sep. 2019 - Present

- 3.51 / 4.0 GPA
- In the Top 10% for 3 semesters

References ___

Senior System Engineer · Ömer Üçler · omer.ucler@arcelik.com

Arçelik Global

• Fehmi is a teammate who can think very analytically, helpful, open to innovation and I enjoy working with him. His ability to understand the systemic problem and make code conversion for it is a feature that makes him different from other employees. I am sure that these features that he has will bring him to a better place in the future.

Senior Software Developer · Mehmet Ali Erol · mehmetalierol@windowslive.com

Ford Otosan

• Fehmi is a great team player, he has good communication skills. He is responsible, contributes and always gladly shares his knowledge. He constantly improves himself, attends trainings and researches new technologies

Prof.Dr. · Ahmet Sayar · ahmet.sayar@kocaeli.edu.tr

Kocaeli University